neoperl.net 2018-08-09

# NEOPERL: General Terms & Conditions

**  
General information**

We take the protection of personal data, and therefore your privacy, very seriously. In this notice, we would like to explain what it means for you when you use our personalised services and how we protect your data. In order to ensure your privacy is protected to the greatest possible extent, we naturally comply with all legal regulations on data protection.

**Personal data  
**Personal data is information about your identity. This includes information such as name, address, telephone number, email address. It is not necessary for you to disclose personal data in order to use our website. In certain cases, however, we need your name, address and other information so that we can provide the services you have requested.

We also need this information, for example, to send you information material, goods you have ordered or to answer questions you have asked us. We will let you know whenever this is the case. In addition, we store and process only data that you provide to us voluntarily or automatically. When we ask you for further data, this is voluntary information. Personal data is only processed to fulfil an offer you have requested and to protect our own legitimate business interests.

**Intended use of personal data  
**We use the personal data you provide to answer your inquiries, process your orders or provide you access to certain information or offers. We will neither sell your personal data to third parties nor market it in any other way.

**Specific use  
**We will collect, process and use the personal data you provide online only for the purposes we have told you about. Your personal data will not be passed on to third parties without your necessary consent. Personal data is only collected and transmitted to government institutions and authorities entitled to receive information in accordance with the relevant laws or if we are obliged to do so by a court decision. Our employees and the service companies commissioned by us are bound to non-disclosure and compliance with the provisions of the German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz, BDSG).

Your personal data will only be stored for as long as is necessary for its processing. This applies so long as no other storage duration is specified in this Privacy Statement or no longer storage duration is required due to legal obligations.

**Data collected automatically  
**When you use our website, the following data is stored for organisational and technical reasons: the names of the pages accessed, the browser and operating system used, the date and time of access, search engines used, names of files downloaded and your IP address. We evaluate this technical data anonymously and for statistical purposes only, in order to be able to continuously optimise our internet presence and make our internet offerings even more attractive. This anonymous data is stored separately from personal information on secure systems and does not allow you to be personally identified. Your personal data and privacy are therefore protected at all times.

**Children**  
People under the age of 16 should not give us any personal data without the consent of their parents or legal guardians. Personal data from children and young people is not requested, collected or passed on to third parties.

**Links**  
This privacy notice does not apply to external links which are available to you within the scope of our website. When we provide links, we endeavour to ensure that they also comply with our data protection and security standards. However, we have no influence over other providers' compliance with data protection and security regulations. Please therefore also read the privacy policies provided on the websites of other providers.

**Contact data**

**Name and address of the controller responsible for processing  
**_Neoperl GmbH  
Klosterrunsstraße 9-11  
79379 Müllheim  
Tel. +49 7631 188 0  
Fax. +49 7631 188 287  
Mail: info@neoperl.de_

**Name and address of the data protection officer  
**_Michael Kranzer  
Bechtle GmbH  
IT-Systemhaus Freiburg  
Leinenweberstraße 1, DE-79108 Freiburg im Breisgau  
datenschutzbeauftragter@neoperl.de_

If you have any questions about data protection, you can contact our data protection officer directly at any time.

**Use of special services on our website**

For certain services (newsletter, etc.), we need to collect personal data. Only the data required for the respective purpose is collected and the legal retention periods are taken into account.

**Newsletter subscribers  
**If you would like to subscribe to the newsletter offered on our website, we require an email address from you as well as information that allows us to verify that the email address belongs to you and that you agree to receive the newsletter. We use the double opt-in procedure to ensure that newsletters are only sent out where consent has been provided. As part of this process, the potential recipient can be included in a distribution list. Subsequently, the user is given the opportunity to confirm their registration in a legally secure manner by means of a confirmation email. The address is only actively included in the distribution list if user confirmation is provided.

We use this data exclusively for sending the requested information and offers.

The newsletter software used is called Newsletter2Go. This means your data will be transmitted to Newsletter2Go GmbH. Newsletter2Go is prohibited from selling your data and using it for purposes other than sending the newsletter. Newsletter2Go is a certified German provider selected in accordance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act.

Further information can be found here: https://www.newsletter2go.co.uk/information-for-newsletter-recipients/

You can revoke your consent to your data and email address being stored and used to send you the newsletter at any time, for example via the "Unsubscribe" link in the newsletter.

**Customer account  
**Personal data is required for a customer account. Required data is marked with an asterisk (*) in the registration process. By registering, you consent to the use of this data for the purpose of managing your account.

**Online application portal  
**We use an online application portal to organise job applications. If you use this online portal, the following personal data is processed: title, first name, surname, house number and street, postcode and town, email address, telephone/mobile number, editable text box for application cover letter, attachment upload for application cover letter and documents. Data is encrypted for transmission. This data is used exclusively for the application procedure. It is passed on internally to the relevant department managers. The data will be deleted 3 months after completion of the application process. If your application leads to the conclusion of a contract, the data is included in your personnel file.

**General information on the use of cookies**

The use of cookies enables us to provide users of our website with more user friendly services. This is not possible without the use of cookies. We optimise our information and offers on the basis of the data collected via cookies. By configuring the browser used, it is possible to prevent the use of cookies for our site. You can also delete cookies that have already been set with a special browser function.

**Information about special cookies**

We use various cookies on our website to analyse the way it is used and to place targeted product adverts. We use technologies from various providers (e.g. Google etc.).

**Piwik (Matomo)  
**Our website uses Piwik. This is a web analysis service. Piwik uses cookies. These are text files which are stored on your computer and enable us to analyse how you use our website. The usage information generated by the cookie (including your truncated IP address) is transmitted to our server and stored for the purpose of usage analysis, which in turn helps us to optimise our website. Your IP address will be immediately made anonymous during this process, so that you as a user remain anonymous to us.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website will not be passed on to third parties. You can prevent the use of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly. In this case, however, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the website. If you do not agree to the storage and analysis of this data from your visit, you can object to this at any time with a mouse click. In this case, an opt-out cookie is stored in your browser, which means that Piwik does not collect any session data.

Please note: if you delete your cookies, the opt-out cookie will also be deleted.

**LiveChat  
**On this website, we use live chat system technology provided by LiveChat Inc. (One International Place Suite 1400, Boston, MA 02110-02619, USA). This LiveChat system allows us to communicate online with you to provide you with quick support whenever you have a question. This is achieved us-ing cookies.

Before you use this service, we inform you about how we process the personal data we collect from you and you must consent to this processing.

The data processing takes place on systems within the EU and in the United States and has been secured by contract. For further information about compliance with the EU GDPR, visit LiveChat Inc. at https://www.livechatinc.com/general-data-protection-regulation/.

**Social media**

**YouTube  
**Our website contains plug-ins from YouTube, part of Google Inc., based in San Bruno, California, USA. The word "YouTube" appears on the YouTube button for easy recognition. When you visit a page of our website that contains such a plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection to the YouTube servers. As part of this, the YouTube server learns which specific page of our website you have accessed. If you are logged into your personal YouTube user account while visiting our website, you enable YouTube to associate your browsing activity directly with your account. If you would like to prevent this data transmission, please log out of YouTube before visiting our website.

The purpose and scope of data collection, further processing and use of the data by YouTube, as well as your rights in this regard and setting options to protect your privacy can be found in the YouTube privacy policy: https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/7671399?p=privacy_guidelines&hl=en-GB.

**XING**  
This website includes programs (plug-ins) from the social network xing.com. This network is operated by XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. On our website, these plug-ins can be recognised by the XING logo. When you visit a part of our website that contains such a plug-in, your browser establishes a direct connection to the XING servers, which in turn transmits the content of the plug-in to your browser and integrates it into the page you are viewing. As a result, the fact that you have visited our website is passed on to XING. If you are logged into your personal XING user account while visiting our website, XING can associate your visit with your account. If you interact with plug-ins, for example clicking XING button, this information is transmitted directly from your browser to XING and stored there.

The purpose and scope of data collection, further processing and use of the data by XING, as well as your rights in this regard and setting options to protect your privacy can be found in the XING privacy policy: https://www.xing.com/app/user?op=tandc&what=dp#.

If you do not want XING to collect data about you via our website, you must log out of XING before visiting our website. You can prevent your IP address being transmitted by not visiting our website.

**LinkedIn**  
Our website uses a function of the LinkedIn network. This network is operated by the LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. If you click the LinkedIn button (plug-in), you will be redirected to our LinkedIn page in a separate browser window and – if you are logged into your LinkedIn user account – you can follow us on LinkedIn. The plug-in establishes a direct connection between your browser and the LinkedIn server. As a result, LinkedIn learns that you have visited our website and your IP address. In addition, if you are logged into your LinkedIn user account, LinkedIn is able to associate your visit to our website with you and your account. We would like to make clear that we have no knowledge of the content of the (personal) data transmitted or how it is used by LinkedIn. For more information, please see LinkedIn's Privacy Policy at: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy.

**Managing and deleting cookies**

You can manage the use of cookies in different ways, depending on the browser you use. Below you will find help for the most common browsers.

Microsoft Explorer:   
https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies

Firefox:  
https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences

Google Chrome:  
https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en

Safari:  
https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_EN

Opera:  
http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html

**Your rights**

You have the right to restrict the use of your personal data at any time. To assert your rights, please contact our data protection officer, whose contact details you will find at the beginning of this document. As the data subject, you can exercise the following rights.

**Right of access  
**Every data subject has the right to receive a summary of the personal data processed in relation to him or her.

**Right to rectification  
**Every data subject has the right to obtain rectification of the personal data processed in relation to him or her.

**Right to erasure  
**Every data subject has the right to obtain the erasure of personal data processed in relation to him or her, provided that no legal obligations prevent this.

**Right to restriction  
**Every data subject has the right to restrict further use of personal data processed in relation to him or her.

**Right to object  
**Every data subject has the right to object to the further use of personal data processed in relation to him or her.

**Right to data portability  
**Every data subject has the right to have the personal data processed in relation to him or her transferred to third parties in a machine-readable format for further use.

**Right to revoke consent  
**Every data subject has the right to revoke the consent granted to process his or her personal data at any time. The lawfulness of the data processing occurring due to the consent granted until its retraction is hereby not affected.

**Complaints  
**Every data subject has the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection supervisory authority in the event of non-compliance with the agreed form of data processing. This supervisory authority can be reached at https://www.baden-wuerttemberg.datenschutz.de/online-beschwerde/.

**Update of data protection information  
**This privacy notice is constantly updated to reflect the latest functions, technologies and applicable legislation. Updates are not made at regular intervals. The privacy policy published on our website is the applicable version.

Version: August 2018
